So good morning,
morning. don't think we have any
backlog of questions to discuss
this week.
I have a few. If you need
material to fill in our
chair or we can just work on
coding kata or do any number of
other things not worried.
Well actually that's what I
that's what my question was
about the file logger kata. I'm
almost done with it, but I'm
having a hard time understanding
exactly what I'm supposed to do
with the last point this I think
it's seventh point. So maybe we
can talk about that. Oh, yeah,
we could always ask everyone,
what do you think of my snow
frog name?
Yeah. I haven't heard of that
before. So he said it's taken on
social media. So somebody else
has thought of it. But if it's
not used by anybody in the dev
space, then I think you totally
use that as a as a name for your
dev brand. Right? There's a game
company in Akron, it's something
frog games. tener what it
is, well, frog probably was a
hoppin frog brewery thing on
that, but I thought there was a
game thing.
I remember there was a bullfrog.
game company, they might not be
around anymore, but they they
were pretty popular in the late
90s. I think early 2000s.
Frog gaming.
Okay. Thanks company that makes
social games. Okay.
And then blue frog? Yeah, these
are not far from me. Cool.
Alright, so you're saying number
seven? With this new
requirements?
Yeah, I guess I am. Because the
way I'm reading this, there's
going to be your you're going to
need to have some sort of state
in there, right to know that, to
know that. Like I saw the first
time you'd like to write so you
need to know that the as you're
logging, whether or not you are
the first entry for the weekend
or not, right. So you need some
sort of flag, I guess.
I mean, you should have all the
state you need in the form of
these log files.
Right. Okay. So that was my
other thinking.
So you could look at the files
and or the contents of the files
and determine whether or not
this is the first time or
whatever of whether you need
that text file.
The files don't have, like each
logging entry doesn't have a
date though. With it, right?
I think what I did when I did
this kind of last was I looked
at the files actual metadata for
when it was created. And
Oh, there you go.
The file info type that you can
read. Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, okay. See, that never
occurred to me to solve that.
Hi, Dennis. How are you? You're
on mute. Good evening, creamer.
Good evening.
Does anyone ever call you
creamer as until like a few days
ago when you decided that that
was your your new name? No,
no, no, no, that's been my name
everywhere. When I left JDs when
I left jdsu. Jason my buddy was
there still and he told me that
Angie in the meeting says, What
the heck is kramers? First Name
anyway, or Kramer's last name?
That is his last name. They all
call me Kramer. Like he said,
you know, with the Kramer from
Seinfeld coming in, that's
pretty much sealed the deal
years ago. So the only time you
use first names in my family is
when there's more of us than one
there.
Okay. Yeah, I'm used to using
last names for people from when
I was in the military. And that
was just how you refer to
everybody. Yeah, that was all
under
uniform. Let's say you strike me
as an Air Force guy.
Army. Although, originally I did
try and go Air Force because I
had a scholarship.
He tried with a scholarship. So
how do you not get there, then?
Oh, it's a long story. I'm
actually wearing my my
university of chicago polo shirt
that I got when I visited there.
A few years ago, my daughter,
but I went to University of
Chicago, out of high school, and
I had a former Air Force ROTC
scholarship. Yeah. And that was
great. And life was good.
Because you know, Chicago is
expensive. And my family didn't
have very much money, and they
could never afford it. But when
I got there, I had to fight with
the bursaries office because
they hadn't been paid by the
scholarship people. So I had to
talk to the Air Force and went
back and forth with them in the
midst of also going to ROTC
classes and all my classes and
everything. And I'm 18. And I
don't know anything. And
eventually what it came down to
was that the Air Force was not,
in fact, going to give me my
scholarship because I had knee
surgery as a sophomore in high
school, which they knew about.
But they were using that as a
reason to rescind my
scholarship, after having
awarded it to me, you know,
eight months earlier at high
school, and when they still
ceremony and everything. Oh,
that's nice. Yeah, so so I ended
up having to leave Chicago after
only being there one quarter,
and I had like $7,000 in debt
from that one quarter that the
Air Force didn't pay. And then I
had to transfer and like start
school, basically a year later,
I went to Ohio State, which is a
lot cheaper. Yes, if I had
decided to go straight to Ohio
State out of high school, I
would have had a full ride
scholarship there because I was
a National Merit finalist. And
they give every one of those a
full ride. But only if you go
there at a high school if you're
a transfer student from another
school, sorry, gotten a
financial aid for you. So
thanks. Thanks, Air Force. Yeah,
thanks a lot. And ultimately,
while I was at Ohio State, I was
ended up talking with some
people and getting convinced
that the Ohio National Guard
would be a good place for me. So
I joined the Army National Guard
and eventually went to ROTC not
with a scholarship at Ohio State
and became an officer and in the
army, you know,
thing wasn't a problem for the
army.
No, no, I mean, it was fine. It
was totally it was there wasn't
even any damage to my knee,
right? They just had done
surgery to look around and see
if there was any damage, or
there was arthroscopic. And so
soccer injury when I was a
sophomore, but yeah, my knees
been fine. Forever.
I'll forgive you for that to
playing soccer. That is
football. Yeah,
I was gonna say at least you
didn't call it football. Yeah,
the
American football
in junior high I played but I
yeah, here in Thailand. They
just put in this little football
they call it over here. Field,
but it's small. So it's like
it's like indoor soccer size,
which to me makes the game like
1000 times better game and yes,
that's what I saw. I played
there like in junior high and
played for what did we play for
three years I played I think.
I'm like yeah, and I ran 400
miles. Oh, by the way I scored
wants to know, it's just like,
it's just like, nothing you do
really matters, you know, most
of the time.
Right? Yeah. A big deal when you
score especially that level
right where it's like a real
team instead of a real team. I
play soccer still, I played a
men's league on Saturday
mornings I just played a pickup
game last night actually. And
like a pickup game we had like a
75 minute period and like 10 on
10 on 10 and we probably score
we don't really keeping track of
the score but it was probably
like 20 to 10 or something at
the end I mean, it was much much
more higher rate of scoring
because neither side had like a
dedicated keeper and yeah, it
was a little more
casual. But that was in on a
small field not on a
relatively it was indoor but it
was a large indoor field. Yeah
actually kind of a goofy field
because it's kind of almost a
square which is just weird.
Yeah, it's wider that needs to
be but it's not nearly as long
as it would be for that with
Yeah, so indoor we played in the
gym, like a basketball court,
right?
Yeah, that's really small. goal
at goalie could score
on goalie i mean it's it's
intense then that it makes it
Much more. Much more fun in my
opinion, right than just running
4000 miles and maybe Good luck.
I mean put your budget sweeper
because you're fast like Yo,
thanks you know I really got to
get a score cuz you're not in
front. Yeah, yeah. I call it a
conditioning for basketball is
what it was.
So Dennis, I said hi earlier how
are you?
Hello? Sorry I didn't get my
headphones to work so I'm fine
How are you?
Good welcome this is Phil and
Kramer if you didn't catch that
and I don't know if anyone else
is joining us today. Thanks for
staying up late tonight to join
in Kramer What time is it for
you?
It's eight o'clock for me so
it'll be like midnight for you
isn't Dan is it Dennis? Is that
how we pronounce it? Because I
know you Finn's play with your
names
I'd see it's correct yes,
Dennis. Okay. Okay good.
Yeah, remember not right with
someone's name just tell me
Alright, so
a little bit more than one
o'clock now so
that's right your followers now?
Yeah. New Zealand like to me New
Zealand looks like it's kind of
close to Thailand but like it's
nowhere really near Thailand.
Well, much closer than you are.
Yeah, when when I arrived here,
I think in Australia is close.
It's good. It's here, neighbor.
But still it's three three hours
on the plane.
Yeah. And are you a native
English speaker Dennis?
And now I'm from Finland. Origin
Okay.
Do you speak Finnish and
Swedish?
I speak Swedish a little bit but
I understand a lot but not very
good.
Okay, so I went when I went
there a hola is mostly Swedish
speaking Finns. Right? Okay,
that's probably was on the west
coast of Finland. So I
was so far north though. It was
way up way up there. way up
there. I flew into Helsinki and
then flew another flight way up
to the north Coachella
is the same color. No, this is a
not a North at all.
Well, Santa wasn't there but he
was warming up.
Alright, so do Do you guys have
any opinions about snow frog as
a as a brand like snow frog dev
as a company name fulfill to us?
Anyone want to say why that's a
horrible name?
No frog. It sounds cartoonish.
So perfect in the developer
world.
Sure. Some things I like about
it are that it's only two
syllables. It's easy to spell
enough to tell anybody how to
spell it. And the break between
the words doesn't have any
vowels. Like that's often a
problem. If you have vowels
between your two words, like if,
if it was like, orange alias or
something, right? Like I'm just
making up two words, I know I
have a vowel in the middle,
which is just to be a horrible
name. Like this gets weird
because of that doesn't come
together very well. When you
make that a domain name, right
or an alias, because if it's all
lowercase, it becomes harder to
figure out like orangey but
what's that? right but with snow
frog, you never have that
problem. So you can make this
all lowercase and it would be
just fine. And it works with the
G at the end too. If you make
that snow frog dev or something
like that then you know you're
you're in good shape for for
that so overall I think that's a
good choice for for a name if
you can find the available
aliases or something close to it
and I think we talked last week
about name checker didn't we? Or
did I only post that here but
that's yeah if you go to
something like name checker here
and you put in this then you can
like super quickly see if how
many green checkmarks there are
whether it's a good choice
that's amazing. And then just
you know run off and grab as
many of these as you want.
Before fill those Oh please.
charge me
they're all green. For squares
not green. Oh wait, they were
they were they were out
checking. It looks like Oh,
you've changed our Dallas okay.
If you
just did snow frog all by itself
and like a bunch of stuffs
taken. So it's not very devilish
look good. So So yeah, so I use
this when I'm trying to come up
with a name for something, it
works. It works well. There's
another one I think that
actually has the E in it.
There's there's a few doesn't
really matter which one you use,
they do the same thing. I guess
that's not, there's no there's
another one out there. But this
is the one I usually end up.
Alright, so Phil, any other
questions for me? Or for the
group on on that front? No. All
right. Well, sounds like
generally people are in favor.
Alright, so any other? Any other
questions or topics? Nope.
Nobody posted anything in slack
to queue up for this this week
session. So we can do some hands
on stuff we can talk about
whatever you like, we can
discuss soccer and military
experience. Oh, wait, we did
that.
Well, maybe. Maybe just a follow
up? like where do you I haven't
registered a domain name and
forever. Where's the best way to
do that nowadays,
I I'm personally using Google
domains, pretty much for most
stuff. I'm not a huge fan of
GoDaddy anymore. But I have
domains in three places. My my
three places are GoDaddy,
because I have a bunch of stuff
that is still there that have
moved Google domains, which is
where I mostly put new stuff.
And then Amazon was at route 53,
or Amazon domains. Because I
have some stuff that's set up in
s3, if you just want a static
page, and that's it, and you
don't expect that you're ever
going to put actual code on this
page. Then Amazon static website
stuff is like just amazingly
simple. It's something to Azure
really needs to take a look at.
So if we go to like, Amazon s3
here, and I'll show you what it
would take to get your site. Me
sign in. Alright, so if we do,
website, this is the hardest
part right here is finding out
where this thing is static
website now. How do we get the
web page?
Like blog about it? I think I
might have a blog about I meant
to blog about it. I don't think
I ever did. Come on. This is
gonna be so disappointing when I
can find it. I've used it a few
times.
It's an s3 site, right? Yeah.
I think see build a web app.
It's an app. It's not registered
domain. Really.
I saw something about website
endpoints.
It's just off of s3. This low
risk entrepreneur thing I think
I made as a website, a sample
site, I think was a website.
Shoot. Let's just try to build a
web app. Maybe that's what
that's Elastic Beanstalk?
No, I don't think so either. I
started with AWS about God knows
how many years ago that was. And
then I quit after I met the the
V the VP of Amazon Web Services.
Yeah. He didn't like him. He was
come to, he was at my neighbors.
And he was dating my neighbor,
sister. My problem with that was
this he was married. And I
thought he was a total prick to
be honest with you. And I'm
like, yeah, never didn't care
for the guy that might just I
shouldn't blame the whole
company. Right? whole
organization doesn't one guy.
He's been gone too, right. So
it's like, you know, not
everybody in there supported
that guy either. But it's still
just gambling. Same thing with
same thing with resharper, the
guy from what's the name of the
company behind resharper
JetBrains. JetBrains did a code
mash presentation five years ago
or something like that? And he
was when they were talking about
their C sharp alternative one,
which I can't remember the name.
And he just talked down about
things, so many things. It just
kind of gave me a bad taste in
my mouth. And I'm like, I don't
want resharper I haven't used it
since. Like I said, I shouldn't
do that because it's just one
person. Right? And it's unfair
to categorize the whole company
with one person but it does show
you that. Be careful what you
say because you can affect your
brain. Yeah.
Okay, you know what, this was so
easy when I did this like a year
ago, and I came in find out how
to do it now. Like they're
showing all these things in here
that are hard. But it was
literally a single page thing.
And I was so impressed with it.
And maybe they've gotten rid of
it, because it was too good.
Like, here's how to host your
static website in 10 steps, this
was like one step. So go to s3,
you don't have to do any of this
crap. Like, this is all this was
all done on this page for you,
he didn't have to do any of it.
So we know what your blog post
is going to be.
Find it. Alright, I'm not gonna
waste more time on this, but But
yeah, if you want to host it,
uh, your domain on Amazon,
theoretically, there's a way to
do a static website pretty
easily. then more importantly,
cheaply, right? If you've got a
one page like brochure website,
or even a couple pages, Amazon
will cost you like 10 cents a
month to host the thing there.
And it'll be lightning fast,
because it's just serving static
HTML. Whereas with GoDaddy,
they'll charge you like $5 or
$10 a month to have some
website, they'll have better
tooling for you to build the
thing, though. And Google
domains, they've got website
building stuff somewhere, too,
but it's, it's not as tightly
integrated. GoDaddy stuff is all
is all nice and integrated.
I'm probably going to start with
just the blog. So
if you want just a blog, then
like, I'm using a shoot, what am
I using? siteground? I think
Yeah. siteground. And that that
has worked well for my blog. So
that when I do know where that
is, that's what tools to do.
Yeah, so I'm using this. And
they are, I use WordPress for
mine. And it's super cheap. I've
got this $12 a month plan where
I was paying to WP Engine
substantially more. And this is
100,000 visits a month, which is
plenty for me.
You register your domain name
with them, or you have to do it
somewhere else.
Mine was somewhere else, they
probably would let you do it. I
mean, most of these places you
can, I wouldn't know Yeah,
register a new domain right
here. 16 bucks, you'd probably
get a cheaper somewhere else.
Google domains is for for
the.com is about as cheap as you
can get.
And CloudFlare is another good
one to know oh
CloudFlare out there as well.
Yeah. CloudFlare actually has
though no markup on their
domains, variability
domain registration, I don't
have any mine with them. But I'm
moving more and more of my DNS
to them. Because they offer some
nice services like automatically
giving you SSL without you
having to buy a certificate. So
I've got a bunch of these sites
like dev better itself is, is
run through CloudFlare. So if
you want HTTPS and CloudFlare
makes it cheap.
Notice that GoDaddy, I think
included also the SSL
certificate with their with
their domain names.
Yes, I would do CloudFlare or,
or Google domains I've got I've
got them in, I think I saw one
left and not GoDaddy, but a
GoDaddy reseller. It's like
domains price range, or
something like that. I don't
know. It's a GoDaddy reseller,
and then donate Google domains
and CloudFlare. That's where
I've got all mine now.
Right. And you can just flip
this thing here and turn until
it crypto SSL turned it on, and
then you get SSL running to your
site. Now, it's not fully
protected, because it's gonna go
from CloudFlare to your site in
HTTP, which will not be
encrypted. But for any client
stuff, it'll be encrypted. So
it's only gonna be like cloud to
cloud that it would be not
secure. Okay, if that makes
sense. Just just keep that in
mind. If you ever like doing
something super secure, that you
really want to be secure, and
not just a blog, right. And then
in terms of traffic for for
siteground, when you say they
they will do up to 100,000
monthly visits. This is my my
blog or Dallas, calm and like
in, let's say March. And also
make sure you set up Google
Analytics because it's really
nice. Man, I'm at like 52,000
sessions. So I'm like, only half
of what that thing will let me
get for 12 bucks. Whereas WP
engine was charging like $50 a
month for up to 25,000 sessions
and then like an extra dollar
for every 1000 after that or
something. So they were they
were hitting me with bills for
that plus bills for bandwidth
plus other stuff. So they were
costing me like $70 a month. And
then they wanted to tell me that
I couldn't even stay on that
plane anymore. And I had to
upgrade to one that was like 107
a month. And that's what finally
made me leave.
Because they're great in terms
of customer service, but they're
just too expensive. Do you guys
use Google Analytics, everybody
can use it.
I just put it back. On my thing
to do, because after I upgraded
to the new ghost, I forgot to
set it back up again. So you
said that I'm like, Oh, yeah, I
need to add that back.
Yeah. So my real estate website
is very useful because we get
stats for each property, how
many views and things like that
it's very, very useful for us.
Nice. So this is dev better,
which was just a one page site
for now, that's hosted on Azure.
And so you know, it doesn't get
quite as much traffic as my site
does. I got a typical day it
gets like six visits. Some days,
something big happens, like I
don't know what happened on
March 29.
I thought of joining and I kept
going back as a tating. Reading.
Alright. So what else we can
talk about everything you need
to set up your, your site,
right? So you've got name
checker to find all your places,
you've got something somewhere
on Amazon to set up a website,
you've got this, if you're doing
a blog, which it sounds like you
are, I would recommend
WordPress, but there's, you
know, a few other people doing a
few different things on here.
I was thinking of trying ghost.
Sure. Just because I hate
WordPress. My real estate
website is is built on the
WordPress template and it's
just, I don't know, I'm having a
really hard time with it. But
that might be my problem and not
the WordPress. But ghost is also
I think, based on node. I'm
familiar with that technology
more than PHP. So I was thinking
just for fun too, cuz I've never
Azure I was thinking of actually
using like, because I think they
know I think they have like
already made images and stuff
like that. But I was thinking of
actually spinning it up myself
on on a VM all that up, because
I I've never really done that
before. So I thought it would be
an interesting learning
experience.
Do you have a subscription?
Azure subscription? Or I mean a
MSDN? subscription? Yeah. So you
get 50 bucks a month?
Yeah, that's what I was thinking
of doing that.
I say 50? That's 150 isn't it?
150 for enterprise pros. 50.
Okay. And if they Microsoft
screws up, you can just get more
and more, I've got like four
accounts that they've never shut
off, like 150 bucks a month. Now
the
problem is you can't pull them
so you got to like manage all
your stuff between different
going on.
Yeah, so you had that two way
back in the day, they like never
figure out with your MSDN
subscription from a previous
company. It just like keeps it
keeps going.
Yeah. That actually have actual
subs with them. But
yeah, so I hadn't marathon and
when Brian switched it over for
me, they put it on my other one.
So now I have both. So I've got
four of these things. One that I
actually pay for now. So I get I
get 50 a month out of it. Just
start
your own blog hosting company
and everybody a dev better can
host their blogs with you.
charge them 20 bucks a month.
Yeah, free Azure hosting. It's
Win win.
There you go. Yeah. When when?
You're using ghost Kramer?
Yeah. Yeah, I use ghosts. I use
the default template. What's
your
hosting?
I don't even know because like I
said, it's, um, it's on Azure. I
used it as your template.
Okay, so it's on Azure.
Yeah, it's a B one, I think I
think is what it is.
Okay. So if you want to know how
to set it up on Azure, just talk
to Kramer.
Yeah. So I went straight simple.
So now I need to go back in and
add Google Analytics back.
Yeah, you should do that.
I had it before but when I
listen,
Pierre, do you guys have blogs
anywhere currently?
I don't know. Yeah, plan. I'm
gonna. I looked up Gatsby. I'm
going to use that to build a
blog this this weekend.
Nice. Gatsby is nice if you're a
react guy.
Yeah, I was looking for Angular
option. I didn't see one I like
Gatsby looked really
interesting.
Well, Angular is not really made
for I would say it's not made
for static sites, whereas Gatsby
is definitely driven towards
towards that so so yeah, Gatsby
react. People are doing Gatsby
somebody else's in the group has
got a Gatsby blog, too. I don't
remember who do you see.
Now but I bet you're right. I do
remember that someone else did.
Yeah, somebody has one.
Yeah, I checked it out and
really liked it and going back
to my old job, and they just
adopted react. So it's You get a
gift for me to kind of refresh
myself with react as well.
When are you gonna publish your
blazer blog engine?
I'm not going to publish it
anytime soon for a blazer blog
engine but but there's a handful
of I know, St. He did one as
well on using blazer as a blog.
But his blog started ghost. It's
just moving so fast. It's just
not there yet.
Hosted live yet, I'm sure. But I
do wonder like if anyone's
seriously building one, like,
commercial? I'm sure they might
just wonder if they're building
it yet.
Yeah. Well, I there's there's
some example, blazer blogs. I
think Chris Sainty is the one
that did it. This way? I say
it's like st with a Y on the
end. Yeah, I'm pretty sure he
did something with a bug in
there.
There's also a Gatsby version
for Vue JS counter with the name
of it. It's called but it's it's
probably really similar.
That's not it that
page. But no, no, it's not.
But anyway, yeah, it's coming.
But I would go. So blazer is an
interesting phenomenon. They're
in that people are talking about
what would you put in
production? Because it's not
production code? And I'm like,
but the fact of the matter is
the vast majority of everything
you're running in blazer
production code. I mean, like,
like, I'm using mediator, that's
the same mediator that's been
running in dotnet. For what,
however, many years and all of
dotnet is production code. So
the only difference is, is where
is it built? And how is it
hosted? So there's some work,
but I mean, once once you get
those kinks, it works. I just
put the crypto wallet out this
weekend. And it's strong blazer,
that was kind of the deal. I
told him I get the right into
whatever the hell I want to
write it or not gonna do it.
And they were happy with that.
They're desperate for mine and
pay me squat. So his friend of
mine, so are you gonna argue
they pay me like 400 bucks a
month, like, Oh, God, I gotta
quit doing that shit, but
smarter, they're gonna start
making money as opposed to just
helping people for free. But I
still enjoy it. So if you don't
have anything, how much
experience do you have in fluent
validation?
I have used it.
I have used it for years. Yeah.
Yeah. So much more complex. I
want to do the more complex
stuff. Number one, number one
would be the knowledge check. So
speaking of that app, let me let
me pull it up real quick. that I
use for validation for my, for
my blazer forms in there. But I
do this double check crap that I
shouldn't have to do.
They should use guard clauses
for that.
No, it's so fluance checking for
if it's required, right? Then I
have something else down the
block. And I know there's a way
to do it. I just pulled up this
video. I'm like, I'm gonna watch
this. So I can quit guessing
you'll share your screen.
I get there in a second. Oh,
crap, it's not gonna work,
because I just upgraded the
damn. SDK. But the code still
work. For me, I can still show
the code. Okay. For some reason,
Microsoft core decided that it
was a good idea to not upgrade
side by side on the on the, on
the previews. Now, if you could
talk to somebody and tell them,
that's the dumbest concept ever,
because the preview people are
the ones that need the side by
side more than anyone.
saralee want to fill up their
hard drive with separate side by
side 20 gig preview install,
takes you
20 seconds to install the dumb
thing. Yeah, that's true. So it
literally breaks your build. So
if you go with the previous
preview, if you got everything
running, and you install the new
one, it you can't compile the
old one anymore without
uninstalling the new one and
compiling the old one. And
typically, you want to say, you
know, was it running before? Did
I break it with the new, you
know, you want to build and
that's the whole point in global
Jason, right is to pick my SDK,
right? And they broke the whole
the whole workflow. So
your problem is that you're not
building with containers, if you
had a Docker container was doing
your build that had the preview
version on it. Container around
and it is the thing that builds
and then you just get a new
container with the new preview
and use that as your build
engine.
Yeah, that's what I said when
they did it. I'm like crap. Now
I don't have to go fire up
Dockers and keep a bunch of
containers hanging around. I
could fill up my whole engine
with containers, which is a
whole lot bigger than
right, right? SDK is not
necessarily bigger than Visual
Studio, but yeah.
Well, I have to put Visual
Studio on the container at least
dotnet
now just on it, yeah, just just
the dotnet runtime. Yeah, but
alright, do you want me to let
you share?
See if I got my link find the
source real quick client
feature.
And are you using? You're using,
you know, verbose, like what's
on my screen right now? things
not not attributes right?
Correct. Correct. Good old. Good
old. Well, fluent. Yeah. So let
me see here. What am I doing?
I'm trying to send edge currency
wallets. Sin has a validator
right here. Okay, so how do I
share
the green button? So sure,
yeah, I'm gonna have to find
that thing because
the zoom window and share your
screen.
share my screen share my screen,
which 1am I on? What do you see?
so far? Nothing. darkness.
Darkness. Oh, oh. You started
screen sharing but nothing's
coming through. Yes, code. Share
your whole screen. Striking
share? screen? Sure. Steven T.
Kramer has started screen share.
It's a field of blackness.
Okay. Well, so much that right?
Copy Paste the code into slack.
Copy Paste the code into Slack,
that'll work. I'll collapse my
regions, and then paste it to
say Japan. All right. Just throw
it into coaching session. Oh,
well, why don't I just give you
the it's all on GitHub. This is
the open source project,
or that that works to
get that that didn't work.
blazer state. Now, that one?
Positive carries anthem gold. So
it's a gold backed crypto.
What's the username, I'm gonna.
Here's the GitHub repo. I'll
paste it into coaching sessions,
I guess. There's that so we go
through some source into the
quiet talk, give you the exact
page and then in the features,
edge, edge currency wallet,
we're gonna do a sin. So we're
actually trying to send some
money and have a send validator
there. So this will be the link
to that.
Sure, I got it.
Yep, that's it. So you'll see if
scroll down a little bit, I do
some, I do some not empty stuff.
destination address, for
example. That second one, see
where I do not empty as on line
29 and 30. And then I do
effectively the same thing on
line 34. On the other, there's
some way better to do that. I
don't know if I put it in a win
in a win clause somehow or
another. So if I wrap that whole
thing to say, maybe, maybe if I
put the not empty check in a
wind clause or something, I
don't know I haven't done it for
a while. I've told my I've
taught my other men by the kids
I apprentice to split study
frickin fluid validation, and
then help me.
So do you have test for this? Is
that how you know whether or not
it works?
Yeah, there's a there's a
there's a test case just for the
validation rules. A ton of them
actually.
So you know whether or not
you're hitting this one, versus
you're hitting this one? Well,
it there's a way that you can
fail out right if on a on a
test. But I wanted to continue
on all, you know, give it give
everybody all the errors that
they have when they submit it
not just the first one, right?
Sure. So I could tell that but
but I but there's some way
inside of validation to tell
that second one to say don't
don't bother to check this guy
if it's empty.
I see. So you only want to check
this address. If you This one
is. And the only reason you need
this is because you're checking
all of them. If this had blown
up and short circuited the whole
validation, yeah, then it got,
Okay, I see the problem now. So,
so you're, you want it to do all
of them. But but still do only
some of them, you know, given
certain traditionally certain
things being there.
Yeah, cuz there's a lot of
they're basically knowledge
checks, right? It's, you'll see
it again down there on line 46.
Or I'm doing another check,
well, obviously, I can't check
greater than zero, which these
are strings, by the way, cuz
they're, they're like numbers,
but they're strings. Cuz they're
big integers effectively. And I
saw I converted to a big end,
but if it's empty, it throws an
exception, right? So I want to,
I want to avoid that exception,
but there's a better way to do
that there's some way
or is there a chain off of rule
for like, I would expect
somewhere on this one for there
to be something like a than or
if valid then or something like
that. So that then you would
only come into this subsequent
rule if, if this rule passed. If
that doesn't exist, then it
should, because then this would
just chain in, and you'd have a
more elegant syntax for those
without having to do this crap
here. That's basically doing
some of the already checked.
I think, if you put the if you
put the when I'm guessing here,
but I think I could put the
whole rule for 4941 there and
42. Inside the when clause.
Inside here.
Yeah, so that's gonna say,
because it only execute the
other stuff if the win is true,
right? So that would actually it
kind of looks backwards. But but
it actually makes sense the
stuff in the when clause gets
executed before the rule does.
And maybe maybe that works.
Maybe it works, I don't know, if
you'd use I know you've you've
mentioned it, but I know how to
do everything. It can do
everything. It's impressive. And
I used to be able to do more,
but I got back to it the other
day, and I'm like, I can't
remember how to do it. But I'm
like, make it work. I got to
ship this thing was two o'clock
in the morning. I'm like, I get
this out.
So and this is all using blazer.
Yeah, that's all using laser.
Nice. So they're all every one
of those. See, those are all
mediator action handler, all of
those guys, right? Oh, I call
them actions when they're on the
client side. And I call them
request and response when they
go to the server just to
distinguish between the two. So
these are client side mediators,
items there. So they'll hit. So
a forum sends that action, it
goes to the handler, and all
uses my uses my blazer state
component. But you haven't done
a code review yet. Tell me if
you think so. encapsulation.
Yeah. encapsulation. So if you
go look at these guys, look at
those state down there. So edge
state, that's good enough.
That'll work.
Okay.
Okay, so these are partial
classes. Well, I broke them up
only in the state that I break
them up this way. So if you look
at the behavior, so I need
certain things to implement it
in order for this thing to work.
So here is you'll see,
and this base type is what
you're getting out of blazer
state. Yeah,
yeah, that base that base state
there is. So I need you to be
able to clone I need an
initialized to initialize the
state when you start at the
client side. So that's what's
there. And then there's another
one, oh, maybe there's no debug
on this one. But normally, I
have a debug one that's
basically conditional compile in
just so that I can do some extra
testing, right.
One nice thing about Visual
Studio 19 2019 is you can just
clone a GitHub repo and have it
open up immediately and
yeah, you go you'll be open up
but I doubt highly if you'll be
able to build because you won't
have the right because of the
stupid side by side you won't
have the right previews required
to build that thing.
Probably not I don't have any
previews. on them, I get it.
Yeah, because it'll just
squatting in doesn't do is pick
this solution automatically. So
that's probably why these loads
are all failing is because maybe
the loads to load should work.
The load should work. Projects
are located there.
So the project just regular
dotnet core projects, right. So
that's Yeah,
yeah. cs project. That's, that's
pretty much my, my structure
there.
Folks. Keep looking at it in
GitHub.
Yeah. Interesting. Interesting
thing though with with blazer,
you have that shared, so your
details that go back and forth.
That folder up there that says
dtos is actually between
JavaScript and blazer, those
That's an interesting thing
phenomenon. Now I actually have
data transfer objects on the
client that go back and forth
between JavaScript interop
is edge meaning client. That
means
no edge is a product. That's the
JavaScript library that I'm
using. So it's an external
JavaScript library.
Okay, so client over here is
client. So that
that is what the webassembly
runs, could run on the server
side, too. But that's the actual
UI client. So this is just an
MVC application. Here, you'll
see it also, if you go to
features. Here, if you can show
you can show my, yeah, just do
the just do the weather forecast
thing. It's about as simple as,
as it gets. That you want to see
the smallest controller on the
planet. Those are pretty small
controllers. They don't I don't
do anything. I just just a model
binder
is not constant for the route.
Yes, that is a very nice
feature, by the way, because now
if you're in a view, and you
want to redirect to a route, you
don't have to do any magic
strings. It's right there. And
that how do you get that it's a
single endpoint per controller.
There's, that's a mistake, in my
opinion, Microsoft did early on
is this, these controllers, I'm
like, you have a stateless
system. And they're separate
endpoints, there is no, there's
no correlation between the
endpoints. Now because somebody
thought that they should have
this rule about slash controller
name, slash action name, that
somehow these things should go
together. And why. So if you get
rid of that philosophy, and you
just say, every controller is a
single endpoint, well, then you
can put all the controller
related stuff right there. So
the route is in that, in this
case, because of, because of
blazer I can share, I can share
objects. So that's what the
shared folder is the request and
the response are shared inside
of the shared project. For the
same, they'll be in the same
structure, I would like for them
to be in the same place, but
right currently have to be in a
different DLL. But you'll see
that request response right
there. So I don't have to create
a DTO. Right, because I use the
same code on blazer, as I do on
the the other side, and I put
the route right in there so that
the request only has one
endpoint. So so that makes sense
as well. On an MVC app, I just
use it on the controller itself,
but in this case, I share it on
the request object as to where
the route goes. But But works
works works pretty nice.
Why am I waiting the request ID?
request ID is just a it's just
something for me to correlate
between requests and responses
and logging. Okay, every one of
them is good, it just gets
randomly created good. So I can
say, so when you log something,
it's this request and which
response because you know,
they're, they're asynchronous so
they may show up in different
orders but you can always match
up a request with its response
Okay, got it.
It don't have to have it
actually but I like it as a
feature so my full validation on
that thing was was I need to
improve but I'll probably blog
about it this week on how to do
those correctly after I watched
this guy's video figured out so
the state the state the way
every one of those handlers will
look at that get application
handler there I hope I have it
on that one. I should so notice
that I'm lying to you
looking for state
Oh hold on let me find all these
handlers should be
Do you want to try and demo this
for us? Maybe next week?
I can sure I absolutely can.
Yeah, yeah, yep. You can see the
website working now the
cryptocurrency but but yeah,
next week I'll put together
we'll do I'll do a blazer state
demo for you
know make sure you've got three
preview builds and all that
Yeah, I'm in the midst of this
week trying to upgrade to the to
the new bits and trying to I'm
on nightly builds now trying to
catch up. Which is also non
trivial. Do you have you done
that? I know you're writing all
the docs
nightly builds. I haven't done
docs for them for a little
while. But a year I think so.
I'm working on architecture
commits last week
to the docs No.
I stopped you remember you
committed something today? SP
dotnet core last week.
Maybe one thing but yeah, if you
go to GitHub comm ASP. NET If
you shop on web go here you shop
on web is my thing yeah that's
what I'm talking about that's
not the back so right that's
that's the architecture stuff
I'm talking about. So yeah I
used to be the number one
contributor on this because I
did all this work way back here
right but then I you know, it
settled down up through middle
of 2017 and then I haven't done
anything much with it since July
of 2017 so all these a full time
folks have passed me and guard
Rex they basically picked him up
because he's super cheap
charging more and so he's been
doing it more since he fell off
he's been doing the docks What's
that? He's been doing the docks
guard Rex I've been seeing him
name quite a bit
yeah, he's doing a lot like I
say he his rate was like half
mine so that's fine he can he
can run with that. But yeah, the
shop on web stuff is a separate
repo separate team at Microsoft.
And that's that's this one. So
if you look at the whatever
insights and commits here
right yeah, but that's a that's
a Microsoft repo
right? Yeah, it's still
Microsoft repo but but this is
what I'm working on. Along with
my friend Eric, who have
enlisted help me.
Yeah, I've tried to keep track
of bro Wow, he
that I haven't seen that. You
see actually patient?
Why, why? turtle Why?
I think I am to
actually have Azure, Azure has
all free. Well, GitHub has free
private repos now to
fill here's a black frog.
GitHub is free. Private repos.
Now.
Yeah, since January 1,
I'm paying for nothing.
Why am I paying them?
So let me see. So GitHub later
state, so I use partial classes
to encapsulate so that the
state, you know, in Redux, they
tell you state needs to be
immutable. I'm not exactly sure
why they tell me that, frankly,
other than the fact that I need
to be able to revert back. Yeah,
that's that's the one. So I use
partial classes in all of my
states.
Now, what's the purpose of this
is to manage your client side
state?
Yep. So think Redux, right.
I don't use react or Redux. So I
can think Redux. But it won't
really do it for
I won't help you. Yeah, so it's
just client side state. So I
need I want to manage the state,
anywhere in the in the app.
Right? So everybody inherits
from this state. And it's a
mediator pipeline. And what it
has, what it does is, which is
really trivial. It's just a
collection, right? It's just a
collection of these things.
And for this state, you're
really just talking about a
collection of data that you're
holding in place, not the state
design pattern where you're
doing straight state transitions
from one state to another.
Correct. It's just this is this
is state like as in what react
would call state, it's just like
the global state for the app,
right? It's in memory database
for the app, right? All right,
for the client side, for all,
that all of the changes take
place through through the
pipeline. So what I do is I
actually clone a clone the state
before any event is handled. So
there's clone, then there is
after that is the actual
handler, which is modify, and
then after that, I fire off
subscriptions. So the so that
the so there's, these are all
this is all done with the with
the mediator. So that was why
you saw on that state before I
had a clone implementation. I
couldn't think of any better way
to do it than then use clone to
clone the state. So some people
don't like clone. But I think
it's a bit odd that it doesn't
return back an object up that's
tight. But I understand why they
did that. But you have to cast
it. So what, right, right. Yeah,
so so whenever anybody mutate
state, they don't have to think
about like in Redux. And Redux,
you have to say, I'm gonna use
my reducer and make sure that I
return a new object. But blazer
state, you just mutate it all
you want. Because I've already
I've already created a new one.
So the paradigm that I typically
do is is that is that we give
you the state and then you
create a new one before you
update the store. Right? I'm
like, Well, if if everything
comes back to me from a handler,
then I know you're going to
change state. So whichever state
that your handler returns, I'll
just give you a copy of that to
start with and then you don't
have to think about it. When you
when you use it, so you can just
mutate state, all you want in
theory seems to work. And I
encapsulate the private part,
that's what I want to show you.
Let me see if I can get to that
real quick. So that the handlers
are actually partial classes.
Let's see JavaScript, let's go
routing. Maybe routing has
actions in there, change route
change route. handler will come
up. So yeah, that works go to
change go to, into source
blazer, state features routing,
actions change route handler. So
this is kind of weird, but so
you see that the change route
handler is a is a actually an
internal class, or a child class
of Route state itself. So this
is how I managed to make sure
everything is private. So that
nobody can modify mutate state,
the handler itself is a is a
child class of the state that it
modifies. Okay. So
so it's only going to be or
nougat package or whatever.
Yeah, but Right, right. So the
point being is, is that, but
this is the way I implement
them. That's a design pattern to
go with for everything, so that
nobody can mutate your state
without going through a handler,
because all of your state's
actually private. But the
interesting part is, is this the
child class of your class has
access to your private parts?
Right? I've used that technique
before as well. It's nice.
Yeah. So I originally back in my
Delphi days, actually, I made a
rule that was like no child
classes, right? Because it just
tend to obfuscate stuff. And
since I've moved to C sharp, I
fallen in love with it as an
encapsulation method that I use
them quite often now.
Yeah, another use I have for
them is, when you're organizing
enums and constants, you can use
that as a technique to get you
know, the ability to drill down
as if they were namespaces still
have everything in one folder.
Right? So if you have a bunch of
constants, you want to group
them, or you can put them into
in your child classes of the
parent class to give you that
same type of discoverability.
You guys understand what I'm
talking about? Philip? Now? So
what he's saying is this route
state has an internal or private
state property, where's rep
state defined? Over in source
over here somewhere? I don't
know where it is. Should have
been right underneath where
you're at? Yeah, so route state
has? Uh,
yeah, would have been somewhere
it would have been, it would
have been that one. That's only
gonna have one route, it's just
gonna have one property called
route.
I see. Right? So this route has
is the data that he's trying to
protect, right. And so it's got
a private setter. So only route
state can set that route, which
it doesn't have any setters to
do it. There's no need any logic
in here to do it. But because
this is a partial class, he can
have another rep state somewhere
else defined that adds
additional functionality, right?
So this one over here, adds to
this partial class of routes.
That does too, but and then the,
the one that we were just
looking at was this change route
handler. And it also despite its
name up here, is actually
defining route state as another
partial class. And so all these
partial classes are going to get
combined together at compile
time as if they were one
definition. Okay? And then this
internal class, which I would,
which you're using as your name
here, so up here, so So even
though it's inside of outstayed,
that's, that's the important
part of of this file. And so
he's using that as a file name.
But it importantly, it has
access to grab state's private
setter, right? So there's a that
that route property somewhere.
This guy is going to touch that.
I don't see it
right there. Line 37.
Oh, yeah. Okay, here. So it's
able to set it. Okay.
Okay. So I wasn't familiar with
the partial class concept, or
even internal.
Yeah, this internal is a
different thing like this, if
you get rid of that this class
could still live inside here.
And that that's called a child
class, I think, is that what
it's called? Or? Yes, I think
so. Class is confusing with
inheritance, too, right? Because
if I inherit a state that's a
child class, to me, it's an
embedded an inner, inner class,
inner. But internal just means
that you can't do anything with
this, this handler outside of
this project this assembly,
okay, nested is a nested
classes, that's what they want
to call it. Alright. So this is
a nested class, I hate that
name, because it's nested with
inside, within wrap state.
nested types is what the docs
goes with.
Alright? Let's try to remember
that. Because you would think
you would call them internal,
that we already use that word
for something and you think we
call them child, but we already
use that for something. It's
like,
what else we call it? Yes, but I
like it. So so it's
encapsulated? Right? I still
maintain the single
responsibility principle,
because this handler doesn't do
anything but one thing. Now one,
one could argue that the route
state itself isn't the single
responsibility, but I would
argue they're wrong. Because
it's the state and everything
that manages it, right?
Well, it depends how complex the
state is, I suppose if it's got
literally one string, then it's
hard to argue that it doesn't
have one responsibility. But if,
if your state for this thing
had, you know, if the class
route state here had like, five
different groups of five
properties that were each do
different things like, yeah,
here's your shipping address,
and here's your, you know, your
billing address, and here's your
credit card details, right?
Those could all be different,
potentially different
responsibilities. But, but I
agree with you that just
managing that state could be
just one responsibility.
So it accomplished my goal of
making it so that nobody, nobody
can actually mutate the state
without going through without
going through the handlers,
which is what the objective is,
when you build a pipeline use
the pipeline, right? I don't
want people being able to
directly mutate it without going
through the pipeline. So sure, I
have
some concepts about the using
nested clauses, which xe can
access private members of parent
class, because for one concern
is discoverability. So when when
I opened my bar in class, I can
see some private members there.
So in this is my context time of
working with. So I, usually when
when I see some private members,
I'm can freely refactor it in
any way, because I know those
are private. And with this
approach of nested class, which
is in some different folder, so
little bit weird, but I know I
use that, but usually I use this
when both classes in the same
file in the same folder, yeah,
or even same file. Like when you
have generated code, and you
want to put your customizations
right next to the generated
code. That's usually when I use
partial classes, the most common
scenario anyway,
but generated code Yeah, so that
you can just blow away the whole
file. So but I'm using them
everything underneath that
routing folder is all related.
So it's, it's in there, I and
if you if you did refactor this,
right, if you said you know what
routes not really a good name,
I'm gonna name this route
string, right? or whatever, you
know, refactor, it'll still
work, right? If you just do a
rename refactoring, it'll,
you'll fix it here, too. If you
refactor it by hand, and you
just change the name here and
you build, the compiler is going
to tell you that it's broken
thing is broken. So I mean, I
agree with you, Dennis, that
it's not as easy to see it all
in one place. But to two things,
one, the compiler will help you
it's not JavaScript. So we have
a compiler and into this code,
nobody else but Kramer should
never have to look at because
it's only in his nougat package.
So his clients of this code
won't have to see it. So as long
as he knows how it's set up in
his team of 1000s of developers
that eventually are going to
support this.
Yeah, I hope but it's a it's a
pretty common pattern. That's
the same the way those are, are
organized anyway is pretty
common. That's a feature folder.
Right or folder concept
coming becoming more common.
Yeah.
Yeah. So So I made the change
route handler there has that
name, and it's it is a nested
class, but it is the only thing
that matters about that
particular class. Right.
I have a question. Sorry, I
noticed you are using using D
directives inside the namespace.
How you will argue it argumented
against using it outside of name
namespace,
what we're using inside the
namespace
using directives. Oh, here,
okay. Yeah, I've seen that
gobos. Actually, Personally, I
prefer having them above but but
there are scenarios where it is
important whether or not they're
inside or outside. It does it
does it just not scenarios I
ever run into.
It does matter, it does matter.
And yeah, it doesn't matter if
you're if you're, it'll make
your namespaces shorter as a
whole if they're on the inside,
because they will automatically
find the ones that it's in. As
far as your as far as what
you're using go. When Microsoft
first came out with stylecop
using usings, for originally
were told to be on the inside of
your namespace. I like it
because it collapses everything
together. So you'll see that's,
that's my default rule is to put
them in the inside. I had some
guy argue with me and tell me
Well, there just won't work in
there. I'm like, Wow, my code
doesn't know that.
Yeah, I always do it the way
that's the default from all the
templates, which is to put it at
the top. I don't know why
Microsoft has that as the
default for the templates. And
some of their guidance says that
this is a better way to do it.
And sometimes, but
I changed the default templates
I actually never I never like
create a template. Mads Mads
Christensen has a has a
component that I think is great.
You just hit Ctrl f2 to create a
new file, and it'll pull out
templates itself. Okay, if you
just type in a.cs, it'll create
the file, it's faster than doing
add new, whatever. And, and he
has pulls in his own templates
from us directory so that it's
easier to modify them as well.
Okay, try to change the internal
templates on Visual Studio, I've
got a blog post on it someplace.
I think that's where the guy is
arguing with me about the USING
clause. Because that's what I
was trying to do. I was trying
to change some of the things. I
also like my item templates.
Well, we got to get this
dependency injection thing, the
same pattern happens over and
over again, why can I just say,
inject this, automatically
create it in the end? Like right
there, you see that you're a
helper, right? So what am I
going to have? I'm gonna have
three things gonna have a
parameter there, I'm gonna have
it in the constructor, and I'm
gonna have a variable. So
TypeScript lets you do this all
in one line.
Yeah, yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Another
mandirs languages, right. But we
should be able to, we should be
able to pull this, I think
there's a refactoring now, that
can do it. But when it creates
that line, 22 there, it'll make
it a public member. But I don't,
if I injected it, there's no
reason for it to ever be public.
Right?
Yeah. Sometimes you want public
properties that are injected? I
mean, a lot of times you don't
but but you could, if you're
making it a property, there's no
reason why it shouldn't be
public, right? If you want it to
be private, why don't you just
make it a field?
Because I can answer that
question too, because I'm a big
fan of runtime type information,
and fields don't have any. So as
a default, and the cost between
the field and the property is
trivial. So I always go with
properties. I just get rid of
all the fields in the world.
Mostly, it's a backing field. So
anytime I ever have a field,
otherwise, I'm gonna have a
properties.
what's what's your runtime type
information that you're using?
Like, what do you need that for?
In this particular case? I'm
not. But you'll see, like,
you'll see plenty of times that
actually I actually do use maybe
not in this code, but I actually
use runtime type information. So
whatever the properties on this
particular object activity,
activator, create instance, and
stuff like that, which, yeah, so
iterate through properties.
But again, that's that's like
exposing the internals, right?
If you want this to actually be
private, then making it a field
makes it more private. Like it's
a bust to me that it doesn't
show up in reflection, if I
don't want it to be exposed.
Well, I guess, but I don't
expect my end users to be using
reflection anyway. Right? But I
do I do use well, like JSON
dotnet and the way it It won't
serialize it won't serialize
something, if it's a private
field, right?
Okay, but you never want Jason
to serialize this because it's a
service.
on that case, true, but I'm just
saying my default is as I go
with, the only difference
between private field and the
private property is runtime type
information.
Okay, I'm not saying you're
always wrong. The reason why I
go in would use a field
typically, is because to me, if
it's a property, that that
implies that a client is going
to work with it, like some other
thing is going to work with it.
That's not always true. But it
would be super rare for me to
have a private property like
this. I might have a private
setter. I might even have like
an internal get or something but
but if it's a property, to me,
the the intent of that contract
is that some other class besides
mine is going to work with it.
And if the only thing that's
ever going to work with it is my
class then I will make that a
field. Because communicates to
me that my design intent is that
it's only for me.
To me fields are worthless. Just
make a frame of properties. Why
do I need to feel
like, properties are different
things is new to me. So we're
just,
this is actually a relatively
recent feature in C sharp It was
like, I don't know, probably C
sharp for maybe that where we
even got these auto properties,
like in the first version of C
sharp, you couldn't do this, the
only thing you could do is
create a backing field and then
have a getter accessor wrapped
around it. So So part of my
preferences, probably just
because I've been working with C
sharp for 20 years or close to
it. What is it been like 17
years now. And before that
things before before this one
was called
Delphi, which is what C sharp
is, by the way. Anders Anders
Hiles Berg created C sharp,
Phil, he also created
TypeScript. And he also created
Delphi and object Pascal. So
when he he left, he left Borland
after creating Delphi and went
to Microsoft and created C
sharp. So we Delphi people joked
that, Oh, this is what Delphi
five was supposed to be. So most
of the Delphi people have left
and followed Anders over. But it
was rather rather easy for us to
pick up C sharp because
literally you just change
beginning to squigglies. And
you're there it is, it is Delphi
except for except for the fact
that Delphi still has one
feature, the C sharp doesn't
have. You can implement
delegates with an object and
then dealt in Delphi, you can't
do that in C sharp. You know,
I'm saying you have an
interface. So if you want to
implement an interface, and you
have a particular object, you
want to be the one to implement
that interface in Delphi, you
can just say, implement the
interface using this this
component, which is quite nice.
Can't do that. But Has anybody
seen the new default interface?
What are your thoughts on that?
default interface
implementations?
Yes. Will people abuse that and
turn that into multiple
inheritance or not? I mean, it's
just reeks to say, Sure, why
not?
Last week, I think, didn't we,
and we looked into it. And it's
not bad. Because if there is a
conflict, you have to fix it at
compile time. So you have to
say, specifically, which
interface you're going to use,
right? If to both have like a
save method, or whatever. It's
like,
what's the difference between
that and multiple inheritance?
Let's say I have three, three
interfaces that I'll have a
default thing. Now I could just
say this object is this an
interface implements these three
interfaces, and it's just like
being
I know, there's there's not much
difference, and maybe in a
future C sharp version, they'll
even support actual multiple
inheritance and decided that
they're okay with the diamond
inheritance problem.
Yeah. So I mean, it's, I
definitely think it's worth
worth implementing some things
in your default implementations,
although the intention is is to
be able to not break to not
break things by changing your
interface that was there. That
was our design goal, but but it
affords us many other maybe bad
habits. But Has anybody else
started using? reference? No
reference? In C sharp?
I have not yet.
So you saw my comment the other
day that the default, the
default type, the default value
for a string? Which can, which
can't be no, is no. Right?
Yes, yes. Well, I mean, but also
it'd be empty string, maybe. But
that breaks all kinds of things.
Well, if I were to design the
language with the no reference
pointers in the first place,
that my guess is it would have
been interesting for a string,
right? And then the nullable
type would have been no. Right?
would have made sense. So now
every time you use a string,
that can't be no, you have to
make sure you end up with a
bunch of properties that say,
string dot empty after this. But
I think it's gonna be great. You
know, we're talking about there.
Guys, who in the group, by the
way, I'm just talking this
conversation with C sharp stuff
that maybe everybody's all
JavaScript people. I don't know.
So who's Phil? I know you're a
TypeScript guy, which I think I
do. I've got some experience
there. Dennis is a C sharp guy.
Right? I'm, I have experienced
with this C sharp last 10 years,
but last two years. I'm working
with the Ruby.
Ruby on Rails. Yeah, Ruby is
supposed to be nice. I haven't
done it.
And Ruby is my day job and then
my hope is C sharp.
Okay, here you're doing C sharp
left, two and a half years.
Yeah, yeah. Yeah. Okay. So the
reference that the null
reference normal reference
types, right? Yeah. nullable
reference types. So a reference
is a pointer to an object. That
before obviously, it could be,
it could be no. But now you can
explicitly tell it whether you
want this thing to be no or not.
So the inevitable error that you
get no reference, you try to
access a null reference pointer.
Now the compiler will be able to
check for that. You can turn it
on and off in. I haven't done
this yet. But you can turn it on
and off in specific areas to two
different levels. There's
enabled and then there's this
like a symbol or something,
isn't it? Steve? What's the
other one called, it's enabled,
and there's another level of it,
and then there's disabled. By
default, it's disabled, because
all of your existing code will
not compile. But I think it's
going to be good. And worth
worth refactoring. So so my
thoughts are
trying to find a syntax for it
here.
Just question mark.
Question mark for nullable.
Yeah, yeah, if it's knowable,
you put the question mark, like
just like, like Phil doesn't
TypeScript.
If I understand correctly, then
the variable still can be now
but you cannot use it. Because
when you try to use non nullable
variable compiler will tell you
about correct. So that's, I
think, like having a default
value or null for the string, it
should be okay. Because you
still you will not be able to
use it.
yourself. It should still throw
a error if you haven't
initialized it.
Yes, yes. Yeah.
Correct. Interesting that you
can use these directives to turn
it on and off.
Yeah, there's another directive
it's enable what's the other one
I forget
enable restore and
that's like another level Yes.
You've heard of it and ever use
it so it takes some it's nice
because it tells you
so for example,
disables the other one other
store disable disable
but there's a different level
besides just enabled something
that does like a little
different type of check. So it's
like not quite as strict. Okay.
You just like you say, so I
can't see it on there. But maybe
I maybe I was dreaming and I
made that up. But don't don't
think I did. But think about it
for a while like Steve has a
guard clauses because how often
you actually check for these
things, right? Because that's
extremely common thing. Every
reference point or you send into
a method you put a guard clause
on right Steve if it's required
I need to guard clause to check
for know if you have this
enabled, you don't need the
guard clause anymore because you
can't get it No.
All forgiving operators the bang
nullability can be oblivious.
Before this feature existed
variables were oblivious to
whether or not they were no.
Yeah, safe only is what you're
after.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, that's it.
Yeah, I was gonna say there's
some other stinking thing in
there that you can do. Yeah.
nullable. And
safe. Only warning. All kinds of
settings for this.
Yeah. Okay. So there's more than
just three. Yeah, but anyway, I
think this is a great spot for
people are moving to C sharp to
turn on up for grabs on their
site. And then let people enable
it enable. It works. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. And then you
can like say you can Clean up,
clean up some guard clauses.
Now the default enablement of
this is done in the XML and your
cs proj. Right. That's your
default setting is project wide
with the latest version here and
double context option here. So
right, that would be the first
thing they would check. They
can't just go in and turn on
like one class in your project.
I mean, they could turn this on
to something that's not fully
enabled, right and do
Yeah, but you Get it down to the
point where you turn it on in
one class,
you do warnings only.
Yeah. So most people are going
to do warnings, right? And then
go back through and, and clean
them up, right. But something to
think about on Greenfield apps,
I would say turn it on enable on
a Greenfield app and use it.
Sure.
We have with our team here is
have a convention for this kind
of stuff. So we never add the
gods for now for constructor
arguments. But we have a
convention like we never pass
now or something. So if you pass
now it's sweet. It will blow up
anyway.
So PC or something for that, how
are you enforcing that?
We're not enforcing this
convention between convention
between the team members,
okay, so So turn it on, it'll
blow
up. It'll blow up is because the
code that's getting the thing
will try and use it and then
it'll get an all reference
exception. Yes. Okay.
I don't I don't remember when I
lost when we got in production.
Knowledge reference exceptions.
So everything key injected
through. Di Di so nice, which is
good.
All right. Well, we are we are
past time. So I'm going to wrap
this up and get this recording
up there. Sorry, this this week
was a little bit all over the
place. We didn't have a lot of
questions, but we had a good
discussion. I think if you guys
have any follow up questions or
or think of anything during the
week, please post them in slack
and I'll talk to you next week.
Alright, thanks, guys. I'll
throw the answers to the fluid
validation on there or a blog
post.
Care guys Thanks, guys.